Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection (MS Hyde 10): Guide.
Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection,
- Steevens, George, 1736-1800. Autograph letter, signed, Hampstead Heath [London] to [Edmond Malone] [1783 May 10?] Saturday., (668); 1s.
  Discusses Samuel Johnson's reaction to Joseph Ritson's Remarks, Critical and Illustrative, on the Text and Notes of the Last Edition of Shakspeare. Mentions an auction of Sir Herbert Croft's books. Annotated on verso by Malone. One corner missing, with some loss of text.
  Croft's auction was also mentioned in a letter from Johnson to Hester Thrale dated 1783 May 8, MS Hyde 1, item (93).
- De Medalle, L. S. (Lydia Sterne), b. 1747. Autograph letter, signed, York (England), to [Thomas Becket?] [1768], (669); 2s.
  From the daughter of Laurence Sterne, concerning the distribution of his A Sentimental Journey through France and Italy.
  [This letter formerly listed in this finding aid as having been written by Laurence Sterne (1713-1768). Corrected by a reader in 2009].
- Steuart, James, Sir, 1712-1780. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to David Stewart Erskine, Earl of Buchan, 1779 Sept. 30., (670); 3s.
  Concerning taxation policy for the distilling industry in Scotland.
- Strahan, George, 1744-1824. Autograph letter, signed, Islington (London), to [Sir Robert Chambers] 1782 July 2., (671); 1s.
  Recommends brother-in-law William Robertson for an India post, and reports on the health of Samuel Johnson.
- Strahan, George, 1744-1824. Autograph letter, signed, [Oxford, England] to Samuel Johnson, 1771 Apr. 5., (672); 2s.
  Testifies to Ralph Plumb's progress as a student of Latin. Strahan's transcript of a sample of Plumb's translation is enclosed.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 230.
- Strahan, George, 1744-1824. Autograph letter, signed, Cheltenham (England), to John Spottiswoode, 1800 July 21., (673); 1s.
- Strahan, William, 1715-1785. Autograph draft letter, signed, London, to unidentified recipient, 1780 Sept. 21., (674); 1s.
  Offering publishing terms on behalf of Strahan Cadell to an unknown author.
- Strahan, William, 1715-1785. Cover: autograph document, signed, [no place] to R.A. Harrison, Esq., of Yorkshire (England), [circa 1774-1784., (674a); 1s.
  Cover panel of a letter, franked by Strahan.
- Strange, Isabella Lumisden, 1721 or 2-1808. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Charlotte A. (Charlotte Anne) Francis (then Charlotte Burney), 1782 Aug. 29., (675); 1s.
  Discusses her son's enlistment in the navy.
- Strathmore, Mary Eleanor Bowes, Countess of, 1749-1800. Autograph letter, signed, St. James's Place [London] to Mr. Johnson, 1782 Feb. 20., (676); 1s.
  Complains of lack of correspondence.
- Stuart, Andrew, 1725-1801. Autograph letter, signed, London, to [John Stewart, Earl of Galloway?] 1790 July 12., (677); 1s.
  Apparently concerning claims to the chieftanship of the Stewart clan, which Stuart researched for the Earl of Galloway during this period.
- Stuart, Gilbert, [1755-1828?] Autograph note, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [17--?] Thursday., (678); 1s.
  Concerning Mr. Saltonstall's bill.
- Suckling, John, Sir, 1609-1642. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Edward Conway, Viscount Conway of Conway Castle, ca. [1639-1640], (679); 1s.
  Anticipates an order to march to Durham (England) in the Bishops' Wars.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 232.
- Suffolk and Berkshire, Henry Howard, Earl of, 1739-1779. Order: autograph document, signed, [no place] [17--], (680); 1s.
  Order to discharge William Earle as receiver of the land tax for Wiltshire (England), and replace him with Edmund Wilkins.
- Sydney, Thomas Townshend, Viscount, 1733-1800. Autograph letter, signed, Albemarle Street [London] to [George Nugent Temple Grenville, Marquess of Buckingham] 1785 July 6., (681); 1s.
  Concerning "Irish business" in Parliament.
- Talbot, Catherine, 1721-1770. Autograph letter, signed, Bristol (England), to Joseph Emïn, 1759 Aug. 12., (682); 1s.
  Sends a letter of introduction for Emïn's use. With postscript by Elizabeth Carter.
- Talfourd, Thomas Noon, Sir, 1795-1854. Autograph letter, signed, London, to William Innell Clement, 1849 Dec. 25., (683); 1s.
  Thanks for gift.
- Taylor, John, 1757-1832. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to J. B. (John Bowyer) Nichols, [1830?], (684); 1s.
  Letter addressed to Nichols for publication in Gentleman's Magazine, concerning John Milton, and Samuel Johnson's misattribution of a Shakespeare quotation.
- Taylor, W. (William), 1765-1836. Autograph letter, signed, Norwich (England), to John Shelley Jr. of Yarmouth (England), 1807 Mar. 12., (685); 1s.
  Concerning the administration of an estate.
- Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892. Autograph note, Aldworth, Haslemere, Surrey (England), to Mr. Jarvis, 1881 Nov. 15., (686); 1s.
  Declines to critique Jarvis's poems.
- Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863. Autograph note, signed, 36 Onslow Square S.W. [London] to David Roberts, 1860 July 13., (687); 1s.
  Declines invitation.
- Thicknesse, Philip, 1719-1792. Autograph letter, signed, Bath (England), to James Dodsley, 1777 Nov. 24., (688); 1s.
  Concerning distribution of A Year's Journey through France and Part of Spain.
- Thompson, John. Autograph letter, signed, Hull (England), to Samuel Johnson, 1782 Feb. 21., (689); 1s.
  Offers a detailed description of the late Robert Levet.
  Quoted in Bruce Redford, ed., The Letters of Samuel Johnson (Princeton, N.J.: Princeton University Press, 1992) IV, 10-11; and in the Oxford Dictionary of National Biography entry for Robert Levet.
- Thornton, Bonnell, 1724-1768. Autograph letter, signed, Orchard Street [London] to [David Henry?] 1768 Apr. 22., (690); 1s.
  Concerning Richard Warner's A Letter to David Garrick, Esq. Concerning a Glossary to the Plays of Shakespeare. Apparently addressed to the editor of Gentleman's Magazine.
- Todd, Henry John, 1763-1845. Autograph letter, signed, Coulsdon (England), to [Thomas Norton Longman?] [1818] Aug. 31., (691); 1s.
  Concerning presentation copies of his edition of Samuel Johnson's A Dictionary of the English Language.
- Todd, Henry John, 1763-1845. Autograph letter, signed, Settrington [Yorkshire, England] to unidentified recipient, [between 1820-1843] Nov. 9, Thursday., (692); 1s.
  Invitation.
- Tooke, John Horne, 1736-1812. Autograph letter, signed, Brentford (London), to Mr. Fountayne, at Mr. Grignion's, Lichfield Street [London] 1770 Aug. 29., (693); 1s.
  Concerning his legal defense.
- Tooke, John Horne, 1736-1812. Autograph letter, signed, Brentford (London), to unidentified recipient, 1769 Sept. 10., (694); 1s.
- Tooke, John Horne, 1736-1812. Certificate: document, signed, New Brentford, Middlesex [London] 1761 July 9., (695); 1s.
  Certificate of residence for Joseph Baker. Signed as John Horne, and also by Richard Howard and William Williams.
- Tooke, John Horne, 1736-1812. Receipt: document, signed, London, 1794 July 8., (696); 1s.
  Receipt to John Towill Rutt for subscription to Epea Ptepoenta, or, The Diversions of Purley.
- Toplady, Augustus, 1740-1778. Signature: autograph document, London, 1766 Feb. 10., (697); 1s.
  Signature and dateline, clipped from a larger document.
- Torrington, George Byng, 1st viscount, 1663-1733. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] 1721 Oct. 4., (698); 1s.
  Receipt for land bank payment, also signed by Robert Walpole, Earl of Orford;; George Baillie; and others. Trimmed, with substantial loss of text.
- Torrington, John Byng, Viscount, 1743-1813. Autograph letter, [no place] to Edmond Malone, [ca. 1784 Dec. 15], (699); 1s.
  Detailed description of Samuel Johnson's last days, obtained by an interview with William Windham's servant Cawston, who attended Johnson.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 46.
- Towers, Joseph, 1737-1799. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1778 Sept. 29., (700); 1s.
  Receipt to George Robinson for rights to his Observations on Mr. Hume's History of England.
- Townshend, George Townshend, Marquis, 1724-1807. Autograph letter, signed, Dublin Castle [Ireland] to unidentified recipient, 1782 Sept. 17., (701); 1s.
  Concerning the difficulty of recruiting and retaining troops in Ireland.
- Townshend, George Townshend, Marquis, 1724-1807. Autograph letter, signed, Raynham [Norfolk, England] to unidentified recipient, 1786 Jan. 23., (702); 1s.
  Offers a recommendation for an unidentified soldier.
- Trevelyan, George Otto, Sir, 1838-1928. Autograph letter, signed, Irish Office, Queen Street [London] to J.E. Jones, Esq., 1884 Aug. 27., (703); 1s.
  Criticizes "primrose poetry."
- Twiss, Horace, 1787-1849. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1820 Mar. 20., (704); 1s.
  Soliciting political support for George Lamb.
- Tyers, Thomas, 1726-1787. Autograph note, signed, [no place] to James Boswell, 1786 Jan. 27., (705); 1s.
  Forwarding a Samuel Johnson anecdote (not included). With autograph endorsement by Boswell.
- Unidentified author. Autograph letter, Paris, to Charlotte Barrett, [between 1825-1843] June 22, Wednesday., (706); 1s.
  Describes travels in France. The author was traveling with her mother, and was a cousin of Barrett (a niece of Fanny Burney who married in 1807). The first Wednesday, June 22, after cessation of hostilities with France was 1825. Charlotte's husband Henry Barrett, mentioned in the letter, died in 1843.
- Unidentified author. 2 manuscript letters, [no place] to Mrs. Galway, 1755 Jan. 1., (707); 2s.
  Apparently forged letters addressed to a Mrs. Galway, with the same text, purporting to be by Samuel Johnson.
  Published as an authentic letter in R.W. Chapman, The Letters of Samuel Johnson (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1952) I, 60. Not included in Bruce Redford's The Letters of Samuel Johnson.
- Unidentified author. Autograph note, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1784 Dec. 18., (708); 1s.
  Invitation to the funeral of Samuel Johnson, from his executors. The handwriting does not match that of any of the three executors: Sir John Hawkins, Sir Joshua Reynolds, or Sir William Scott.
- Unidentified author. An Auld Scots Ballad: manuscript, [no place] [17--?], (709); 1s.
  Satirical ballad denouncing Thomas Paine, revolution, and atheism.
- Unidentified author. Inscription: manuscript transcript, [London] 1851., (710); 1s.
  Transcript of a plaque placed at Samuel Johnson's pew at St. Clements Danes Church in London in 1851.
- Unidentified author. The Legacy of an Old Friend and His Last Moral Lesson to Mrs. Hester Lynch Thrale now Mrs. Piozzi: autograph manuscript, [circa 1784-1833], (710a); 1s.
  Poem concerning the marriages of Hester Lynch Piozzi. On verso, a fragment of a cover panel addressed to John Thomas Smith.
  *2003JM-35.
- Unidentified author. Memento brogues: manuscript document, [no place] [18--?], (711); 1s.
  An artifact label possibly used for a museum exhibit on Samuel Johnson, reading in full, "Memento, Brogues from the Isle of Sky, such as described by Dr. Johnston in his account of the Hebrides." Brogues are a form of shoe.
- Unidentified author. Notes on Johnson: autograph manuscript, [no place] [18--?], (712); 1v. (4 leaves)
  A short biography of Samuel Johnson in an unknown hand, covering only the years 1709 to 1737, which appears to be an abridged paraphrase of James Boswell's The Life of Samuel Johnson, LL.D. Found among a collection of letters from the Sir Robert Chambers family.
- Upcott, William, 1779-1845. Autograph letter, signed, Oaklands, near St. Albans (England), to Samuel Simpson, Esq. of Lancaster [England] 1845 Mar. 3., (713); 1s.
  Concerning autograph collections.
- Upcott, William, 1779-1845. Autograph letter, signed, London Institution [London] to John Thomas Smith, 1825 June 4., (714); 2s.
  Reports on the recent Sotheby auction of James Boswell material, and presents Smith with the proof sheets of Samuel Johnson's Life of Cowley.
- Ustinov, Peter. And yet those who is manu: Autograph manuscript, [no place] 1957 Dec. 15., (715); 1s.
  Stage prop representing Samuel Johnson's final letter, written by Ustinov in the title role in The Life of Samuel Johnson for the Omnibus television show. Written on the verso of a typescript letter from Hazel D. Svatos, Chicago (Ill.), to the National Broadcasting Company ca. 1951 Dec., complaining about the content of the Bob and Ray Show.
- Vallancey, Charles, 1721-1812. Autograph letter, signed, Dublin (Ireland), to Richard Gough, 1783 Oct. 3., (716); 2s.
  Concerning Gough's edition of William Camden's Britannia; or, A Chorographical Description of the Flourishing Kingdoms of England, Scotland, and Ireland.
- Vallancey, Charles, 1721-1812. Autograph letter, signed, Dublin Society, Hawkins Street [Dublin, Ireland] to unidentified recipient, 1801 May 3., (717); 1s.
  Concerning the publications of the Dublin Society.
- Vestris, Auguste, 1760-1842. Receipts: documents, signed, [no place] 1791., (718); 2s.
  Two signed excise tax receipts (one incompletely filled out). In French.
- Victor, Benjamin, d. 1778. Autograph letter, signed, Dublin (Ireland), to Robert Dodsley, 1754 Jan. 14., (719); 1s.
  Discusses legal issues concerning the manuscript he has submitted.
- Victor Amadeus I, King of Sardinia, 1666-1732. Letter, signed, Turin (Italy), to Conte di Castellamonte, 1703 Oct. 28., (720); 1s.
  Military affairs. In French.
- Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901. Autograph letter, signed, Buckingham Palace [London] to Augusta Wilhelmina Louisa, Duchess of Cambridge, 1837 Nov. 14., (721); 1s.
  Sends birthday greetings.
- Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901. Autograph letter, signed, Windsor Castle [Berkshire, England] to Lady Susan, 1854 Nov. 20., (722); 1s.
- Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901. Order to pay: document, signed, Windsor [Berkshire, England] 1842 Nov. 15., (723); 1s.
  Authorization of pension for Elspeth Morrice, widow of Capt. William Morrice.
- Vincent, William, 1739-1815. Autograph note, signed, Deanery [Westminster, London] to unidentified recipient, [between 1803-1815] Wednesday., (724); 1s.
  Arranging a visit to Mrs. Woodfall.
- Voltaire, 1694-1778. Autograph note, [no place] to Mr. Forbes Leith, [1769], (725); 1s.
  Invitation, in English.
- Voltaire, 1694-1778. Autograph letter, [no place] to [Horace Bénédict?] de Saussure, [17--], (726); 1s.
- Walker, Joseph C. (Joseph Cooper), d. 1810. Autograph letter, signed, Dublin (Ireland), to unidentified recipient, 1797 June 28., (727); 1s.
  Concerning a copy of James Cavanah Murphy's Travels in Portugal, and Charlotte Turner Smith's Marchmont.
- Walker, Thomas, 1698-1744. Title page: printed document, signed, [no place] [17--], (728); 1s.
  Walker's signature on printed title page of The Rover, or, The Banish't Cavaliers: As it is Acted at His Royal Highness the Duke's Theatre (London: Printed for John Amery, 1677). Also signed on verso. Mounted with For the Benefit of Mr. Walker, an engraving by Anna Maria Ireland after William Hogarth, ca. 1800.
- Wall, John, 1708-1776. Manuscript letter, Worcester (England), to [A. W.] 1760 Jan. 30., (729); 1s.
  Manuscript transcript, apparently made by the recipient of the letter for the purpose of publication. Includes a transcript of a letter from Mary Whateley Darwall to Eliza Logan, [no place] [1760 Jan.?] discussing Samuel Johnson's Rasselas, and a transcript of Whateley's untitled poem beginning To you Eliza be these lines consign'd.
  Gentleman's Magazine 31 (1761), p. 635. Poem published in Mrs. Darwell, Original Poems on Several Occasions (London: R. and J. Dodsley, 1764) as Liberty, an Elegy.
- Wallace, George, 1727-1805. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to William Strahan, 1772 Sept. 25., (730); 1s.
  Concerning church politics and family news.
- Wallace, Matthew, 1728-1771 [?] Autograph letter, signed, Tenterden (England), to William Strahan, 1762 Oct. 12., (731); 1s.
  Concerning his Letters to a Young Nobleman. Mentions Samuel Johnson's pension.
- Walmsley, Gilbert, 1680-1751. Autograph letter, signed, Lichfield (England), to John Colson, 1737 Mar. 2., (732); 1s.
  Letter of introduction for Samuel Johnson and David Garrick, evidently carried by them from Lichfield on their first journey to London. Mounted with typescript transcript.
  L.F. Powell, ed., Boswell's Life of Johnson (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1934) 1, 102.
- Walpole, Horace, 1717-1797. Autograph letter, [no place] to John Pinkerton, [1786 Jan.] Friday., (733); 1s.
  Praising Pinkerton's comments on Samuel Johnson.
- Warburton, William, 1698-1779. Autograph letter, signed, [Newark, Nottinghamshire, England] to William Bowyer, [17-- Apr. 19], (734); 1s.
  Concerning revisions to an unidentified book.
- Warburton, William, 1698-1779. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Robert or James] Dodsley, [17--] Feb. 4., (735); 1s.
  Concerning negotiations with an unnamed author.
- Warburton, William, 1698-1779. Autograph letter, signed, Prior Park [Bath, England] to J. (John) Nourse, 1760 June 23., (736); 1s.
  Requesting books.
- Warren, Richard, 1731-1797. Autograph note, [no place] to Sir Joseph Banks, 1778 Nov. 23., (737); 1s.
  Pledges support for Banks in election for president of the Royal Society.
- Warren, Samuel, 1807-1877. Autograph letter, signed, 12 King's Bench Walk, Inner Temple [London] to [Benjamin?] Webster, 1845 Nov. 26., (738); 1s.
  Asks Webster to produce and star in his new comedy.
- Warton, Joseph, 1722-1800. Manuscript transcript letter, Winchester (England), to William Hayley, 1784 Mar. 19., (739); 1s.
  Commenting on Hayley's plays. Contemporary transcript in an unknown hand.
- Warton, Joseph, 1722-1800. 2 autograph letters, signed, Winchester (England), to J. (John) Nourse, 1762-1764., (740); 2s.
  Concerning orders for books.
- Webster, Noah, 1758-1843. The American spelling book: autograph manuscript, [no place] [1828?], (741); 2s.
  Fragment of an early draft of Webster's 1828 dictionary, giving definitions of "bird," "birdcatcher" and several related words. The "bird" definition includes a reference to Samuel Johnson's definition from A Dictionary of the English Language. Accompanied by a presentation letter from Webster's daughter Eliza Steele Webster Jones, Bridgeport (Conn.), to Harry B. Myers, 1876 Apr. 15.
- Wesley, Charles, 1707-1788. Autograph letter, M. Stafford's [Bristol, England?] to his wife Sarah Gwynne Wesley, [between1749-1771] Aug. 24, Wednesday., (742); 1s.
  Describes his visits to various Methodists.
- Wesley, John, 1703-1791. 2 autograph letters, signed, London, to John Bredin, of Kilbeggan [Ireland] 1780 Nov. 3., (743); 2s.
  The 1780 Nov. 3 letter (not definitely addressed to Bredin) concerns expulsion of disorderly members of the church. The 1781 Feb. 21 letter discusses medical uses of electricity.
- Wesley, Sarah, 1759-1828. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Thomas Maurice] [between 1819-1822], (744); 1s.
  Comments on his memoir, and shares her memories of Samuel Johnson.
- West, Benjamin, 1738-1820. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to John Bell, 1814 July 8., (745); 1s.
  Sends text for printing (not included).
- West, Benjamin, 1738-1820. Autograph letter, signed, Newman Street [London] to Mrs. Elizabeth Carmichael, 1818 July 15., (746); 1s.
  Grants permission to make copies from his sketches.
- West, Benjamin, 1738-1820. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Sir Thomas Lawrence, 1816 July 13., (747); 1s.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 257.
- West, Benjamin, 1738-1820. Admission ticket: document, signed, London, 1819 Jan. 14., (748); 1s.
  Ticket issued to Thomas Hartley for a lecture at the Royal Academy of Art, signed by West as president.
- Weston, Phipps, 1737 or 8-1794. 2 autograph letters, signed, [no place] to Sir Robert Chambers, 1767 May., (749); 2s.
  Concerning a request by George III, King of Great Britain, to see a copy of Chambers's lectures. Both letters mention Samuel Johnson. Damaged, with some loss of text.
- White, Henry, 1761-1836. Autograph letter, Lichfield (England), to [John] Buckler, 1806 Aug. 26., (750); 1s.
  Concerning prints.
- Whitefoord, Caleb, 1734-1810. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] 1802 Feb. 2., (751); 1s.
  Receipt to Charles Cartwright for donation to the Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain).
- Whyte, S. (Samuel), 1733-1811. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Thomas Moore (1779-1851), [ca. 1795?], (752); 1s.
  Sends books to aid Moore's future studies.
- Wilkes, John, 1727-1797. Autograph letter, signed, [London] to Thomas Edwards (1699-1757), 1747 Nov. 24., (753); 1s.
  Sends greetings.
- Wilkes, John, 1727-1797. Autograph letter, signed, Aylesbury (England), to his father Israel Wilkes, 1752 Oct. 22., (754); 1s.
  Concerning the role of his brothers in the family brewery.
- Wilkes, John, 1727-1797. Autograph letter, Brighthelmston (England), to unidentified recipient, [17--] July 1, Sunday., (755); 1s.
  Thanks for comments on speech. Extract, in quotation marks. The letter appears to be in Wilkes's hand, but may be by a different author.
- Wilkes, John, 1727-1797. Affidavit: document, signed, London, 1775 Oct. 4., (756); 1s.
  Signature as mayor, on a signed affidavit by Robert Pitches concerning the handwriting of Thomas Greive.
- Wilkes, John, 1727-1797. Ayliffe and Fox when called, in days of old: autograph manuscript, [no place] [not before 1771?], (757); 1s.
  Satirical poem on John Ayloffe and Charles James Fox, with an introductory line from Juvenal.
- Wilkes, John, 1727-1797. Orders to pay: documents, signed, [London] 1775 Oct. 18., (758); 2s.
  Two orders for payment of rewards in criminal investigations, signed by Wilkes as mayor and John Glynn as recorder. Signed by various reward recipients on verso.
- Wilkie, David, Sir, 1785-1841. Autograph letter, signed, Dunmow, Essex (England), to Mrs. Coppard, of 82 Great Portland Street, London, 1810 Nov. 6., (759); 1s.
  Describes his visit to Sir George Howland Beaumont.
- Williamson, Richard, 1802-1865. Autograph letter, Dean's Yard, Westminster [London] to Miss Waters, of Batheaston [Somerset, England] 1830 Oct. 18., (760); 1s.
  Sends a Richard Porson autograph for her collection.
- Wilson, Thomas, 1747-1813. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Samuel Johnson, [1783?], (761); 1s.
  Dedication letter for his An Archaeological Dictionary.
- Wilson, William Worcester. 2 manuscript letters, Deptford [London] to Commissioners for Victualing His Majesty's Navy, 1767 Jan., (762); 2s.
  Agreeing to a settlement for vicarage properties occupied for naval use. Manuscript transcripts by Henry Pelham.
- Windham, William, 1750-1810. Autograph letter, signed, Hill Street [London] to Philippe d'Auvergne, 1794 Oct. 21., (763); 1s.
  Concerning naval affairs in Jersey and Guernsey (Channel Islands).
- Windham, William, 1750-1810. Autograph letter, signed, Newmarket [London] to John Heaviside, 1809 July 31., (764); 1s.
  Sends a donation for the poor of Conduit Street.
- Windham, William, 1750-1810. Autograph letter, signed, Norwich (England), to Edmond Malone, 1792 Mar. 25., (765); 2s.
  Concerning a membership election for the Literary Club; opposes James Boswell's candidates. With cover.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 262.
- Windham, William, 1750-1810. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [ca. 1790-1799], (766); 1s.
  Requests a convoy for ship departing from Yarmouth (England) to the Elbe River.
- Wise, Henry, b. 1706. Autograph letter, signed, Priory, Warwick (England), to his niece Lady Anna Maria Huggins Gatehouse, 1770 Feb. 9., (767); 1s.
  Listing five generations of their Tilson family ancestors.
- Woolston, Thomas, 1670-1733. Autograph letter, signed, Moor Gate Coffee House, London, to unidentified recipient, [17--?] Oct. 18., (768); 1s.
  Sends present.